coatsandclark.com 2017-06-13

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | Make It Coats

Cookies on our site

Cookies are small text files held on your computer. They allow us to give you the best browsing experience possible and mean we can understand how you use our site. Some cookies have already been set. You can delete and block cookies but your experience may be impacted. By using our website you accept our use of cookies.

By viewing or using this Website, you are agreeing to the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy:

## Personal Information Collected

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" means any information, required by the Website to submit in order to proceed, and by which you can be personally identified, and includes your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, account number, and similar information. This Website will not collect any Personal Information about individuals except where it is specifically, voluntarily, and knowingly provided by them.

The Personal Information collected will be used to send you the information you have requested and to provide information that may be useful to you. We may share non-personal, aggregate statistics (group data) about our site visitors’ traffic patterns with partners or other parties; however, we do not sell or share any Personal Information about individual users.

## Use and Retention of Personal Information

It is Coats & Clark’s policy to maintain all Personal Information as confidential, regardless of the purpose for which it is submitted, and to use such Personal Information only for the following purposes:  

(a) For the specific purpose for which it was volunteered; 

(b) To track our visitors’ use of the Website for internal market research; and 

(c) To notify our visitors of updates to the Website, promotional product opportunities, or other services or products that we think you will find valuable and interesting.  

It is Coats & Clark’s policy to keep Personal Information only for so long as needed for such purposes.

Coats & Clark does not sell, rent or otherwise distribute to third parties Personal Information about visitors to the Website, except as needed for Coats & Clark to provide the services for which such Personal Information was volunteered. The Website contains links to sites controlled by, and pages maintained by, independent third parties.

Coats & Clark does not control use of Personal Information provided to such third parties. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect Personal Information from you which will then be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from this Privacy Policy.

Given the global nature of both the Internet and Coats & Clark / Coats Ltd., using the Internet to collect and process Personal Information usually involves the transmission of data on an international basis.  By browsing the Website and communicating electronically with us, you agree that we may export Personal Information to one or more of our offices in other countries and process it there in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Although data may be held in countries that do not have strict data privacy laws, we do take steps to maintain the privacy and security of your Personal Information.

## Protection of Children's Privacy

Coats & Clark / Coats Ltd. does not knowingly collect personal information of any sort from children under the age of 13.

If Coats & Clark becomes aware that it has inadvertently gathered personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our system.

You have a right to review Personal Information about you that is held by Coats & Clark. To obtain a copy of your personal information, or to request deletion of all Personal Information about you in Coats & Clark’s possession,

please submit your request to our Consumer Services department as set out in the “[Contact Us](http://www.makeitcoats.com/en-us/contactus)” section of the Website.

## Compromised Personal Information

Coats & Clark will notify residents of California, as promptly as commercially possible,

if their Personal information becomes or has been compromised, pursuant to the provisions of California law.

A cookie is a piece of text which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree (or your browser agrees automatically if you have set it up in that way), your browser adds that text in a small file.

A cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets website operators know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We have included a full list of the cookies used on [Makeitcoats.com](http://www.makeitcoats.com/en-us "Makeitcoats.com") below, along with a definition of what the cookie is used for. Make It Coats will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

### How to control and delete cookies

We know that people have concerns about cookies, but we believe that the benefit that you and Make It Coats gain from their proper use is worthwhile.

You can delete the files that contain cookies – those files are stored as part of your internet browser. If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by [Makeitcoats.com](http://www.makeitcoats.com/en-us "Makeitcoats.com"), or indeed any other website, or if you wish to receive notification of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how. Please be aware that declining or denying cookies may prevent you from being able to use the website to its highest capability.

Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "www.aboutcookies.org") which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile device you will need to refer to your manual.

 **This is a list of the main cookies set by the Make It Coats website, and what each is used for:**

ASPXAUTH: The ASP.NET forms authentication cookie name (cookie expires after you close your browser).   
country: A custom cookie to store a country selection from the drop down (lasts for 1 year).   
CoatsCraftsCookie: Indicates you've clicked "Continue" in the cookie information bar (last 1 month).   
ASP.NET_SessionId: The ASP.NET session cookie used to maintain any data for a user session such as Level 1 Brand filter(cookie expires after you close your browser).

 **3rd party cookies:**

AddThis Cookies

uid: Uniquely assigned machine-generated user ID   
di/dt: Maintenance cookies that help manage expiration for other cookies   
bt: User interest modeling   
uvc:Measures how often we see an AddThis user   
ssc/psc/uvc: These cookies are used in recording user sharing and social activity   
loc: Geolocation, used to help publishers know approximately where people sharing information are located. (State level)

Cloudflare

_cfduid: This Cloudflare cookie is used to override any security restrictions based on the IP address you are coming from.

For example, if you are in a coffee shop where there are a bunch of infected machines, but your machine is known to Cloudflare as trusted, then this cookie can override the security setting. It does not store personal information and is strictly necessary for site security operations. It can't be turned off. This cookie expires after 6 years.

Google Analytics

_utma: This Google Analytics cookie keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred. This cookie expires after 2 years.

_utmb: This Google Analytics cookie helps calculate how long a visit takes by collecting a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters the site. This cookie expires after 30 minutes.

_utmc: This Google Analytics cookie helps calculate how long a visit takes by collecting a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves the site. It stays for 30 minutes for another pageview to happen, and if it doesn’t, it expires. This cookie expires after you close your browser.

_utmz: This Google Analytics cookie keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine was used, what link was clicked on, what keywords were used, and where in the world the site was accessed from. This cookie expires after you close your browser.

[Makeitcoats.com](http://www.makeitcoats.com/en-us/ "Makeitcoats.com") uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie in order to evaluate our use of our website and compile reports on user activity.

Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using [Makeitcoats.com](http://www.makeitcoats.com/en-us "Makeitcoats.com"), you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

Make It Coats uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online for the purpose of retaining consumers who have left the site without registering for an account or signing up for a newsletter. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show your ads on sites across the Internet. Make It Coats and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to your website. Google won't allow another advertiser to use your remarketing lists or similar audiences lists without your consent.

The invalidity of any term, condition, or provision of this Privacy Statement & Legal Notice shall not affect the enforceability of those portions of the Privacy Policy deemed enforceable by applicable courts of law.
